《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
ATHENA: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我叫李・阿达玛
My name is Lee Adama,
我爱卡拉・瑟瑞丝!
and I love Kara Thrace!
你听到消息了吗?  我们结婚了!你能相信吗?
Did you hear the news? We got married, can you believe it?
不
No.
不  我不相信
No, I can't believe it.
祝贺你  山姆  祝好运  你会用得着的
Congratulations, Sam, and good luck. You're gonna need it.
我想你    我也想你啊
I missed you. I missed you, too.
不惜一切代价保护那孩子的生命
GAETA: The child's life must be protected at all costs.
第一个人类与赛昂人的混血儿 这真是个上帝的奇迹
The first Cylon-human hybrid. It truly is a miracle from God.
这孩子不会交给赛昂人来抚养
This child will not be raised by the Cylon,
我不会让赛昂人间在这个事情上沾边的
and we cannot risk Cylon agents getting their hands on it.
这我已经决定了
I've made my decision.
我们失去她了
We lost her.
我们尽力了  但她还是死了 就这样结束了
We did the best we could, but she's dead and that's all there is to it.
直到赛昂人相信  这孩子已经不存在
ROSLIN: As far as the Cylons know, this child no longer exists.
那就好了  就行了
That is a good, good thing.
是赫拉
It's Hera.
上帝的第一个新子民
The first of God's new generation.
你看到其余五名赛昂人的脸了吗?
Have you seen the faces of the other five Cylons?
没人见过他们吗?
The ones that no one has seen?
你为什么对他们感兴趣?  我可能是个赛昂人
Why do you want to know about them? I could be a Cylon.
我以为我们的食物供应是取之不竭的
KAT: I thought our food supply was inexhaustible.
食物生产系统已经被污染
The food manufacturing system's been contaminated.
我们只能这样了  直到雅典娜回来
If we just hold on until Athena gets back,
这海藻能保证我们活着
this algae can keep us alive indefinitely.
有一条路穿过那个星团 我找到了那个星球
There's a way through the star cluster, and I found the planet.
正如我们所预计的  这里有一大片海藻
There's huge swathes of algae, just like we thought.
这边有更多的
WOMAN 1: There's some more over here.
好 我只要再…     大概45米…
MAN 1: All right, I'll just have one... MAN 2: About 45 meters...
14英尺的宽度  真的不错
Fourteen inch intake. Yeah, that's great.
把它们装上去摞在一起
MAN 1: Just pack them and stack them,
对  放那边
and put them along this back wall. Right there.
我得到了你的光线数据    好的 把那些…
MAN 3: I got your meter readings for the light. MAN 4: All right. Get those in...
这些可以装上第一艘猛禽 那些装在第二艘猛禽里
All this can go in the first Raptor, all that can go in the second one.
需要帮忙吗?  噢  好啊
Need a hand? Yeah.
再过几天就好了 然后离开这个恶臭的地方
Well, in a couple more days, we can wrap this up, get away from this stench.
其实飞船里和这里差不多一样臭
It stinks as bad up here as it does down there.
至少它吃上去和闻上去味道差不多  是啊
At least it tastes as good as it smells. Yeah.
呵呵  这可是我们的早、午、晚饭
Well, it's breakfast, lunch and dinner until
直到有人找到一个梦想中的星球
someone finds a hot fudge planet.
看  那是什么?
Now what is this?
那他妈的到底是谁?
Who the hell is that?
星芭  我猜是她
It's Starbuck, I guess.
这个礼拜的第三次了
Third time this week.
真不可思意能以机头向上的姿势降落
It's amazing how she keeps landing on the top of the pilot rotation.
噢  别又围在一起掷硬币
Oh, donut runs are assigned off a coin flip.
卡拉可能觉得她遇到了一连串的坏运气
Kara probably thinks she's running a stream of bad luck.
我想我应该过去一下
You know, I should probably get over there.
我想逃掉例会去歇一歇 如果你不介意的话
I'm gonna skip the meet and greet this time if you don't mind.
当然不介意
Sure.
你不觉得把飞机降落得太"爽"了吗?
You brought her in a little hot, don't you think?
是啊  我知道  我在被打分
Yeah, well, had I known I was being graded,
我完成了几个滚筒动作
I would have thrown in a couple barrel rolls.
别忘了提醒我谢谢CAG
Remind me to thank the CAG
要不然就轮不到我来地面了
for sticking me on these crap donut runs, huh?
太不可思议了  你知道吗?
This is insane, you know.
哈
Uh-huh.
这正是我喜欢的方式
That's just the way I like it.
我们要不要开始清空这些帐篷?
Should we start emptying the tents?
嗯  先把这里清理干净然后再弄帐篷
Yeah. Get this cleared up first, and then get to the tents.
好的
Okay.
这儿
Here.
好
Good.
我都不敢正眼看小杜
I can barely look Dee in the eye.
我们得想想办法
We've got to do something about this.
好啊  比如说?
Okay, like what?
我不知道
I don't know.
离婚怎么样?
Like divorce.
哦   嗯
Uh-uh. Mmm-mmm.
啊  拜托  让我们面对现实吧
Oh, come on, let's get real here.
是你自己说事情很糟糕
You said yourself, things were bad.
你的婚姻已经名存实亡了
Your marriage is failing.
不错  不过婚姻是神圣的
Yeah, but marriage is a sacrament.
那不是金字塔游戏  你不能...
It's not a Pyramid game. You don't...
你不能亵渎神圣的 李
You don't get do-overs, Lee.
我已经在上帝面前发过誓了
I made a vow in the sight of the Gods
我不会违背我的诺言
and I'm not gonna break that.
每一次我们这样干的时候 你都在违背那个诺言
You're breaking it every time we do this.
每一次都是
Every time.
话不能这么说的
Divorce is different.
这正是在改变规则
This is just bending the rules.
不行  对不起.我做不到…
No, no. I'm sorry, I...
我做不到… 我不能再过这样的生活了
I can't. I can't live like this.
每一次我看着我的妻子 我都会在她的眼神里看到我的罪过
Every time I look at my wife, I see my own guilt reflected in her eyes.
哇  李  你还挺有诗意的
Oh, wow. Wow, Lee, that is really poetic of you,
但你用不着想得那么多
but you don't need to make that big of a deal out of this.
听着  这件事情对我很重要  卡拉
Well, it is a big deal, Kara, it is.
很重要
It is.
好吧
Okay.
这样吧  我不会离婚 你也不用再偷偷摸摸了
So I won't divorce and you won't cheat.
那我们俩会怎样?
So where does that leave us?
深陷其中
Trapped.
最后五个赛昂人是谁?
Who are the Final Five?
我可能是个赛昂人
I could be a Cylon.
她不太对劲
She's not well.
怎么了  赫拉?
What's the matter, Hera?
没事的  赫拉
It's okay, Hera.
没事的
It's okay.
我在这儿陪着你呢
I'm here for you.
我们的碳同位素测定显示
TYROL: Our initial radio carbon dating
这座庙至少有4 000年历史了
suggests the Temple's at least 4,000 years old,
正好和第十三个部落大批离去的时间相符
which lines up with the exodus of the Thirteenth Tribe.
你真的认为你已经找到了那五人的圣庙?
ROSLIN: Do you really think you've found the Temple of Five?
是的
Yeah.
我是从我父亲关于此方面研究的书上认出来的 总统女士
I recognize it from the books in my father's study, Madam President.
他是个牧师 而这五人圣庙是我们信仰中重要的组成部分
He was a priest and the Temple of Five was an important part of our faith...
应该说是他的信仰
Well, his faith, anyway.
这个地方是不是可能和朱庇特之眼有关  军士长?
Could this place be related to the Eye of Jupiter, Chief?
你理解我的意思了  总统女士
TYROL: You got me, Madam President.
我只隐约记得一些 我在我父亲不注意的时候
All I know is the stuff I kind of remember
在他的研究中偷偷看到的东西
from sneaking into my dad's study when he wasn't looking.
朱庇特之眼? 这到底是讲什么的?
The Eye of Jupiter. What exactly are we talking about?
据圣卷轴上所说
According to the scriptures,
是一个被第十三个部落所遗落的记号
it's a marker that was left behind by the Thirteenth Tribe.
它应该能指出前往地球的道路
It's supposed to point the way to Earth.
军士长  进入警戒状态  我是阿达玛
Chief, we're on alert. This is Adama.
上将  我是盖塔中尉  在作战指挥中心里
Admiral, Lieutenant Gaeta in the CIC.
我们的雷达探测到数个目标
We have multiple dradis contacts.
4艘赛昂基地之星刚刚跳跃过来
Four Cylon baseships just jumped into view.
我马上到
On our way!
报告情况
Sitrep.
4艘基地之星以高速靠近
Four baseships inbound at high speed.
4艘?
Four!
实际上  这些狗娘养的正好跳跃到我们上方
Bastards practically jumped right on top of us.
舰队正在启动超光速飞行引擎  长官
HOSHI: Fleet's spooling up their FTL drives, sir.
准备跳跃到紧急状况坐标 听您的命令
Preparing to jump to emergency stand-by coordinates on your command.
执行     是的  长官
Do it. Aye, sir.
我们必须保持现有位置  直到所有人都归航才可以离开
We gotta hold this position until everyone's back on board.
有多少人在下面?    很多
How many are down there? Enough.
上将  如果朱庇特之眼真的在那座神庙里
Admiral, if the Eye of Jupiter is somewhere in that Temple
而且它真的指明了通往地球的道路
and it really is a marker on the way to Earth...
那我们决不能让赛昂人得到它!
We can't let the Cylons get their hands on it.
准备发射蝮蛇战机
Standby to launch Vipers.
有什么地方不对劲?  赛昂人并没有发射突袭机
Something's odd here. Cylons aren't launching Raiders.
这些基地之星并没有靠近 全都保持在武器射程之外
Baseships are standing off, outside of weapons range.
真是奇怪
That is odd.
上将
Admiral.
是赛昂基地之星 请求和您通话
It's the Cylon baseship, requesting to speak with you.
帮我接通通讯频道
Put it through the speaker.
我是阿达玛上将
This is Admiral Adama.
上将
Admiral,
我真的无法形容听到您的声音是多么的高兴
I can't tell you what a genuine pleasure it is to hear your voice.
我是盖尤斯・波塔尔
This is Gaius Baltar.
我真不敢相信你让赛昂人登上这艘船
ROSLIN: I can't believe we're allowing Cylons on this ship.
他们一定是情况不妙了
They must want something pretty bad
否则在他们刚刚跳跃过来时 就该进攻了
or else they would've started shooting as soon as they jumped in.
那他们为什么要派波塔尔过来?
Why would they send Baltar?
他们明知道 我们不会相信他的任何一句鬼话
They've got to know we won't believe a word he says.
他愿意说什么就让他说什么
He can say whatever he wants.
他说得越多
The longer he talks,
我们就能争取越多的时间让李他们撤回来
the more time we have to get Lee and his people off of the planet.
这里气氛紧张  是不是啊?
It feels like old times, doesn't it?
我真不敢相信我是多么地想念这个地方
I can't believe how much I actually miss this place.
你知道你不可能回来了
You know you can't return.
他们会把你从最近的减压舱扔出去 然后举办个盛大的庆祝晚会
They'd toss you out the nearest airlock, and then throw a party.
是啊  我知道
Yes, I know.
但我还是禁不住觉得我终于...
Still, I can't help the feeling I'm finally
回家了
home.
如果你真的是个赛昂人 最后那终极五人中的一个
If you're really a Cylon, a member of the Final Five,
那么这种感觉也就只是你程序的一部分了
these feelings are just part of your programming,
用来伪装的
part of your cover.
如果我最终真的只是个人类
And if I'm a human being after all?
而不是终极五人之一
If I'm not one of the Final Five,
那么这就是我最后一次有机会见到我的同类了
then this is the last chance I'll ever get to see my kind again.
上校  等一下
Colonel, wait.
啊  看看这个  我们应该敬礼吗?
Well, look at this. Should we salute?
那是布玛尔
That's Boomer.
向老头子开枪的那个吗?
TIGH: The one who shot the old man?
看来你刚刚失去了访问本舰的权力
Well, you just lost your visiting privileges.
让那个东西待在这儿直到我们回来
Hold that thing here until we get back.
是  长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
你们三个继续跟着来
You three, keep on moving.
劳拉
Laura.
劳拉  我...
Laura, I...
真高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
武器就不需要了吧
Weapons are hardly necessary.
是的  一点儿没错
Yes, exactly.
我们这次来没有任何动武的意思
We come in peace.
你们想要什么?
What do you want?
我们想要朱庇特之眼
We want the Eye of Jupiter.
现在让我们把所有的不信任还有反对  统统丢掉
So let's just skip all the denials and protestations,
直接来说我们所知道的
and go straight to it.
你的人现在就在下面的星球上
We know that you have people on the ground,
我们也知道你们找到了第十三部落最初的聚居地
and we know that you've found the original settlement of the Thirteenth Tribe.
而且我们也很容易推测出
It also doesn't take a lot of deduction to conclude
那个让你们不惜更大的损失而不马上逃走的唯一原因
that the only reason you haven't cut your losses and jumped away by now
就是你们可能已经找到了朱庇特之眼
is that you've probably found the artifact,
但是你们还没有把它带回到舰上
but you haven't been able to retrieve it yet.
我说得对吗  总统女士?
Is that about right, Madam President?
我们的人是在那个星球上
We have our people on the surface.
我们不能扔下他们不管
We're not leaving them behind.
那是个很感人  但是没什么说服力的解释
That's a touching, but not very convincing idea.
我们在这个小小的星球上偶然相遇的可能性
Look, the chances that we've all converged on this small planet
极其微小
at the same time are infinitesimally small.
那么看来我们都明白这并不是意外
So, we will understand it's not chance.
你们想得到朱庇特之眼  赛昂人也想得到它
You want the Eye, the Cylons want the Eye.
我想分析一下眼下现实的问题
I would like to discuss the practical issues that come to hand,
那就是一些...
and there are some,
让我们可以达成共识的东西
so that we can reach some accommodation.
这个人说得越少  事情越好办
The less this man says, the better this will go.
等一下
Wait a minute.
如果不是因为我  赛昂人早就在刚刚跳跃过来的时候
If it wasn't for me, the Cylons would have blown you out of the sky
就把你们炸上天了
two seconds after we'd arrived.
我想你可以单独处理好这件事情 如果你可以忍受的了的话
I think you can handle this alone, if you can stomach it.
这样一来  我救了你一命…
So, I've saved your life
再一次
again.
已经是第几次了?  我都有些记不清了
How many times is that, now? Because I'm beginning to lose count.
如果不是我  你们早就全死光了!
If it wasn't for me, you'd all be dead!
你们能开出什么价码?
What's your offer?
你们把朱比特之眼交给我们 我们放你们走
You give us the Eye of Jupiter, we'll let you go.
然后我们会交出波塔尔
And we'll throw in Baltar.
你到底在说些什么?      的确
What are you talking about now? Indeed.
你在说什么 ?      我在即兴而谈
What's he saying? I'm improvising.
放入更多可以换来合作的筹码
Throw in something to sweeten the pot.
另外我觉得上将和总统女士
Besides, I suspect that the Admiral and Madam President
都愿意与他们曾经的领导者在一起单独相处一会儿
would enjoy some nice, quiet, private time with the former leader.
我说得对吧?
Am I right?
的确值得考虑
Worth thinking about.
显然我们在考虑
Definitely worth thinking about.
如果不是那身制服 这里再也不会是你的家了
Despite that uniform, it's not your home anymore.
我做出了自己的决定 我也知道自己忠诚于哪方
I've made my choice and I know where my loyalties lie.
那如果我告诉你  你的女儿还活着呢?
What if I told you that your daughter was still alive?
那我只能说你在撒谎
I'd say you were lying.
确实有人在说谎
Well, someone's lying.
但决不是我
But it's not me.
赫拉还活着
Hera's alive.
至少现在还是
At least for now.
她病了  但我们不知道是什么引起的
She's ill, and we don't know why.
是吗?
Yeah, right.
在新卡布里卡大撤退时  波塔尔发现了她
Baltar found her on New Caprica during the evacuation.
她现在在我们的基地之星上
She's on our baseship right now.
据我们所了解 她当时被藏在劳拉・罗丝琳的学校里
From what we could gather, she was hidden at Laura Roslin's school,
也就是说罗丝琳可能事先布置好了所有的一切
which means that she probably planned the whole thing in the first place.
我不想听这些  看住她
I don't need to listen to this. Watch her.
他们想让你以为你的女儿死了
They let you think that she was dead!
你不会对一个人类做出那样的事 只会对一个"东西"这么做
You don't do that to a person, you do that to a thing!
你的那些朋友们也是这样看你的  莎伦
That's what your friends think of you, Sharon!
你不是他们中的一员  你只是一架机器
You're not one of them! You're a thing!
我们不会把通往地球的钥匙给你们的
We're not giving you the key to finding Earth.
你休想将朱比特之眼从那个星球带到你舰上
You try bringing it up from that planet and see what happens.
我们现在是4比1
We outnumber you four to one.
现在我说了算
I'm setting the terms now.
只要你胆敢对卡拉狄加或是在那个星球上的人发动进攻
Make any attempt to attack this ship or the people on the planet's surface,
我就会把我所有的核武器
I'll launch every nuke I've got.
扔到那个星球上
Lay waste to the entire continent.
你在虚张声势
You're bluffing.
你和我们一样想找到地球
You want to find Earth as much as we do.
守卫  把他们带回他们船上去
Guards, escort them back to their ship.
是  长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
我怎么样才能知道我们在找什么呢?
APOLLO: Well, it would help if I knew what I was looking for.
他真的像一只眼睛吗?
Does it really look like an eye?
我不知道  李
ROSLIN: I don't know, Lee.
我看过圣卷轴  那上面有提到
I've looked at the scriptures and they make reference
朱比特之眼被放在某种寺庙里
to the Eye being left in some sort of Temple,
但却没有特别的描述
but there's no physical description.
我们只知道它会指明通往地球的路
All we know for sure is that it supposedly points the way to Earth.
你相信那些吗?
And you believe that?
赛昂人相信 我不敢说他们就是对的
The Cylons do. I can't take a chance that they're right.
如果他们试图进入那寺庙
If it looks like they're gonna get into the Temple,
给你的命令是把那庙炸毁
your order is to blow it.
明白了  我有多少时间？
Understood. What's my...
怎么回事儿?
What's going on?
赛昂人在干扰 所有频道都是
The Cylons are jamming the wireless, every frequency.
我们要想办法恢复通信
Okay, we need to establish hard communications,
想出个防守这寺庙的计划 同时让泰罗尔继续搜索
work out a plan to defend this Temple while Tyrol searches.
用什么来防守? 十几个陆战队员和五个军官?
Defend it with what? A dozen Marines, maybe five more military?
我们只好征召平民入伍
We're gonna have to draft the civilians.
我可以提一个你肯定不喜欢的建议吗?
Can I make a suggestion that you won't like?
你的建议什么时候让人舒服过?
Do you make any other kind?
让山姆来指挥那些民兵
Use Sam to command the civilians.
你在开玩笑吧
You're not serious.
李       你好  山姆
Lee. Hey, Sam.
嗨
Hi.
我听说你也下来了
Heard you were coming down.
除非有紧急情况  这段时间 我们还真难在一起
Guess it takes an emergency to get us in the same room these days.
我们能否迟些再说这个
Can we do this later, please?
山姆  我们想让你指挥民兵
APOLLO: Sam, I need you to command the civilians.
把他们变成战队小分队
Form them into fire teams.
我会通过军士部署命令....    哇 哇
I'll give my deployment orders through Sergeant... Whoa, whoa.
等等  部署命令?  战斗小分队?
Wait. Deployment orders? Fire teams?
有些人根本就没拿过枪
Come on, some of these guys have never even held a rifle before.
在把平民训练成士兵方面  你应该是专家了
Well, you're supposed to be the expert in turning civilians into soldiers.
不  不  不  我们那时是游击队
No, no, no. We were guerilla fighters.
知道吗?打一枪
All right? Hit and run.
换一个地方 让敌人手忙脚乱
Keep moving, keep the enemy off-balance.
我从来没有防守过一块固定阵地 这可是完全不同的
I've never had to defend a fixed position, that's a whole different game.
这样的话  那你只好尽快学会怎么去做了
Well, then, you're just gonna have to learn it fast,
因为我们已经决定了 我们要防守这个固定阵地
because that's what we're doing, we're defending this fixed position
直到军士长找到朱比特之眼
until the Chief finds this Eye of Jupiter.
好啊  你是想让我们冒着生命危险
Oh, okay, so you want us to risk our lives
去保护一些你还没有找到的东西?!
for something that you haven't even found yet?
听着  山姆 我甚至不清楚那鬼东西是不是真的存在
Listen, Sam, I'm not even sure it exists.
但我没必要告诉你所有那些他妈的细节
But I don't have to tell you every little gods-damn detail...
你知道你需要跟我解释什么吗?
No, you know what you have to explain to me...
嗨 嗨
Hey, hey, hey...
少校负责这次行动  清楚吗?
The Major's in charge of this one, okay?
好吗?
Okay?
哼
Huh.
是啊  我当然不想打扰你和你的少校
Well, I certainly wouldn't want to step between you and your Major.
我想一切进展顺利
Well, I thought that went really well.
他会服从命令的
He'll do it.
他最好是
He better.
我想尼克
I miss Nicky.
你觉得他一切都好吗？
Do you think he's okay?
是的  他一定很好
Yes, he's fine.
他在卡拉狄加上 不会有事的
He's on Galactica. He's fine.
我也希望是
I know.
我小的时候曾恨所有关于信仰的东西
You know, when I was growing up, I hated everything about the faith,
那些规矩  那些仪式  那些永无休止的饭桌上的争论
the rules, the rituals, endless discussions at the dinner table.
我曾经偷偷进入我妈妈用来祈祷的房间 那是最神圣的地方
I used to sneak into my mom's prayer room, you know, holiest of the holies,
我会光着身子拿着黄色杂志跳来跳去 就是想藐视神灵
and I would dance around naked with porn magazines just to defy the Gods
让他们都滚开
and tell them to frak off.
我意思是  我不知道是怎么来到这个地方的
I mean, I don't even know how I found this place.
我只是觉得想开始...走路  然后突然间  我就在这儿了
I just got this urge to start walking, and then suddenly here it is.
当你在这里的时候 你应该看看自己的表情
Well, you should see the look on your face when you're in here.
是一种敬仰
There's this reverence.
甚至说话都轻声了不少
You even talk softer.
我能在这儿感觉到什么
I feel something in here.
一些接近真理的东西
Something true.
但我确实正在这里布置引线 在这个特殊的地方
But here I am setting charges in this special place.
最为神圣的地方
The holiest of the holies. This is
这个五人神庙
the Temple of Five.
如果我父母看到这些
If my parents could see this.
看到我正准备把它炸掉
And I'm gonna blow it up.
我注意到一些不正常的恒星辐射
GAETA: I noticed some anomalies in the solar radiation belt.
我对这个星系恒星的震动模式进行了分析
I made an analysis of the star's vibration modes.
很确定的是  这颗恒星很不稳定
Sure enough, it appears to be highly unstable.
如果你愿意相信的话 它即将转变成一颗超新星
If you can believe it, on the verge of going supernova.
何时?
When?
可能是明天  也可能是一年后
It could be tomorrow, it could be next year.
无法知道确切时间  长官
There's no way of knowing for sure, sir.
一旦它开始转变 我们唯一可能感测到的警报
When it does happen, the only warning that we're likely to get
将是疾速的氦闪光 那时我们将不得不在
is a fast helium flash, at which point we'll have to jump out of here
整个星系被摧毁之前马上离开这里
before it obliterates the entire planetary system.
长官  我并不是那些寻找神谕的人之一
Sir, I'm not one to look for religious signs,
但我实在是想不明白一些奇怪的事情
but I can't get my head around these odds.
人类和赛昂人竟然在这颗星相遇
That human and Cylon both converge on this planet at this exact moment,
就在它即将转变成超新星的时候
just as the star is about to go supernova?
我不是个信仰宗教的人  盖塔先生  你们都知道
I'm not a religious person, Mr. Gaeta, as you both know.
如果这是神灵的旨意
So if this is the work of a higher power,
那他们这次可是幽默过了头
then they have one hell of a sense of humor.
我们在相持 很容易预知
We have a stand-off. Very predictable.
他们拥有朱比特之眼
They have the Eye,
如果我们试图夺走它  他们会用核武器毁掉它
and they'll nuke it if we try to take it,
如果他们试图把它带回到卡拉狄加上 我们会把他们摧毁
and we'll shoot them down if they try bringing it up to Galactica.
你确定他们找到了朱比特之眼吗?
Are we sure they have it?
我们怎么知道他们不是在虚张声势?
How do we know they're not bluffing?
不知道
You don't.
我们三个认为我们不应该冒险行事
We Threes feel that we can't afford to take the chance.
我觉得我们失去了大局观
I think we're missing the big picture here.
我们有机会在这个宇宙中永远去除
We have the opportunity to rid the universe
人类这块顽疾
of the human pestilence once and for all.
我们可以在拿到朱比特之眼
We can discuss that after we get the Eye of Jupiter,
并找到地球之后再讨论这个问题
after we find the path to Earth.
让我来指明那其实并不重要 无论我们是在5天之内找到地球
Let me point out that it doesn't matter if we find Earth in five days,
又或是要花上5000年的时间
or if we find Earth in 5,000 years.
我们毕竟是机器
We're machines,
我们会最终成为欣赏那伟大奇迹的人
we'll still be around to savor the great miracle.
所以任由他们毁掉朱比特之眼吧
So let them destroy the Eye,
如果他们真的已经得到了它
if indeed they have it.
我们必须把握好这千载难逢的时机
We have to take advantage of the situation
消灭卡拉狄加以除后患
and take down Galactica once and for all.
或者我们就在这里待着什么也不做
Or we could stand here and do nothing.
我们并不是没有行动  卡维尔
We're not doing nothing, Cavil.
行动正在进行
Plans are in motion.
对不起  不过那是什么意思?
I'm sorry. What was that?
戴安娜
D'Anna.
我们一跳跃过来 就派遣重型运输机
I've put a Heavy Raider down on the planet's surface
去了星球表面
as soon as we jumped in.
我想那将是我们最好的机会来躲避他们的雷达探测
I thought that would be our best chance of slipping by their dradis.
看来我们成功了
Seems I was right.
有什么特别的原因解释为何我们没有被通知参与策划的吗?
Was there any particular reason the rest of us weren't involved in this decision?
这是个"需要通知"的任务
It was a need-to-know mission.
所以现在我告诉你们  因为你们需要知道
So, now I am telling you, because you need to know.
重点是 我们已经切断了人类部队之间的通讯联络
The point is, we have cut off their troops' communications
而且我们的部队已经登陆到星球上
and we have put our own troops on the ground.
只要我们夺过朱比特之眼
So, as soon as the Centurions retrieve the Eye,
你们就可以摧毁卡拉狄加了
you can take out Galactica.
好了  这就是我们的方案  我们没有选择余地
Okay, here's the deal. We're out of options.
赛昂人把我们看得死死的
The Cylons have got us pinned on this rock
我们唯一的出路就是
and our only way out of here is to hold this place
在卡拉狄加的救援到来前守住这个地方
until Galactica can send a rescue party.
所以  我要把大家分成两队  听好了嘛?
So I've divided you into two teams, okay?
第一队负责向整个营地分发弹药
Team One is gonna be distributing ammunition throughout the camp.
第二队负责制造泰里恩地雷
Team Two is gonna be making homemade tylium mines.
很好
Great. Great.
我知道这不是什么伟大的动作
I know that's not glamorous work,
但是在赛昂人向我们射击的时候
but we're gonna need the extra firepower
我们需要点火力
in case the Cylons decide to take a shot at us.
我知道你们中有些人害怕
Look, I know some of you are scared,
这种情况正常的  因为我也在害怕
and that's okay, because I'm scared, too.
但是我们只要保持冷静 做好该做的事 就能成功
But if we keep our heads and we do our jobs, we can do this.
我们可以一起离开这个地方的
We can all get out of here in one piece.
这里是你们的名字还有各自的任务
Now, Barolay has the list of your names and your assignments.
大家都要记好了  我们外面碰头
Make sure you get with her. I'll see you outside.
说实话  你讲得真不错
That was good, honest.
你是个好的领导
You'd make a good officer.
好领导?
An officer, huh?
就像你?
Like you?
说起来都道貌岸然的 做起来就不一回事了
Someone who swears an oath and knows how to keep it?
我不清楚你讲的是什么意思
I'm not really sure what you think is going on...
别惹我  听到没有?  我不是笨蛋
Don't insult me, okay. I'm not stupid.
我了解我老婆  我了解她是什么样人
I know my wife. I know how she is.
我们结婚都有一年半了
We've been married for a year-and-a-half.
什么 你以为你是第一个?
What, you think you're the first?
我选择和卡拉结婚  那是我的事情
I chose to marry Kara. That's my business.
但是你
But you?
我不清楚你他妈的到底想干什么
I don't know what the hell you think you're trying to do.
我在准备打仗
Look, I'm trying to fight a war.
我在想如何把大家一起带离这个地方
I'm trying to get these people off this rock in one piece.
任务第一  少校
Anything for the cause, Major.
盖尤斯  我差点就看到了剩下的那五个赛昂人
Gaius, I am on the verge of seeing the faces of the Final Five Cylons.
可能是神的脸庞呢
Maybe the face of God himself.
五束神谕之光升起 穿透日光
The Five Lights of the apocalypse rising, struggling towards the light,
只有进入神庙的人才能看到神谕 只有上天选中的人
sins revealed only to those who enter the Temple, only to the Chosen One...
选中的人 选中的人
The Chosen One... The Chosen One...
他们五个在等着我  选中的人
The Five await me. The Chosen One...
盖尤斯  我离真相是如此的近
Gaius, I'm so close to knowing the truth.
什么真相
CAPRICA SIX: What truth?
卡布里卡
Caprica.
我原以为我们三个一直都可以分享些什么
I'd like to think that we three have shared something,
都能越过分出彼此的隔膜
have transcended the barriers that separate people,
但是现在  不知为什么  时间越长
and yet, somehow, the more time goes on,
我越感觉到自己像个局外的人
the more I find myself on the outside looking in.
好吧  根本就不是你想的那样 对吧?
Well, that's not the case at all, is it?
因为我们三个  是个整体
Because we three, we're integral,
我们是一部份.  我们结束了
we're part of... We're finished.
波塔尔和我的命运跟你没关系 卡布里卡
Baltar and my destiny lie separate from yours, Caprica.
五道光芒只会出现在进入神庙的人面前
The Five Lights will be revealed only to those who enter the Temple.
我们一定要下到那个星球去
We have to go down to the planet.
只有你和我才能看到
Only you and I can see this through.
你在找什么?
What are you after?
你们追寻的到底是什么秘密?
What is this secret that you keep pursuing?
你们必须告诉我真相
You have to tell me the truth.
我爱你们
I love you both.
我们也爱你
We love you, too.
但这是你不能和我们共享的
But this is something you cannot share with us.
是你们不能和我共享的?
Something I can't share with you?
在别人都想让你死的时候  我还爱着你
I loved you when everyone else wanted you dead.
那  听好了  你不能误解我们
Now, look, you mustn't misunderstand.
这不是我们个人的事情
It's not personal.
这是先行者的事 这就像你过去所说的  先行者的事
It's transcendent. It's like what you said, it's transcendent.
为我们祈祷吧  卡布里卡
Pray for us, Caprica.
我们也为你祈祷
We'll be praying for you.
好的  他想让我们去设置个前方观察哨
Okay, he wants us to set up forward observation posts
需要用有线连接到我们的大本营
hardwired back to base for communications.
设立的位置一定要在战略交叉点上
The obs are gonna be staggered at strategic locations,
这样如果出现赛昂人  能尽可能多的给我们预警
giving us as much warning as possible if there is a Cylon advance.
而我们只有一架猛禽机 就由瑟瑞丝上尉负责驾驶过去侦查
Since we only have one Raptor, Captain Thrace will fly point.
噢  爽死了
Oh, joy.
无线通信不能用 所以如果你碰上他们的时候 不要和他们交火
Wireless is dead, so if you do make contact, do not engage.
要在近距离干扰他们的信号
Fly to the closest observation post,
然后就马上赶回大本营
have them relay the information back to command.
一定要了解到火力情况 他们的行进方向  还有地点
Be sure to note force strength, direction of march and position.
我都想了两遍了  中尉
I have flown recon once or twice, Lieutenant.
格里戈斯  你和瓦里奇要在这里搭设个观察哨
Griggs, you and Varrick are gonna set up an observation post here.
亨涅克和迪特  你们去这里
Henick and Ditko, you go here.
那谁是幸运的三号呢?
And who gets lucky number three?
那是菲舍尔军士和我
That would be Sergeant Fischer and me.
你还有什么问题吗  上尉?
Do you have a problem with that, Captain?
没 我们1小时内出发
No. We go in an hour.
大本营  这里是火狐一号  大本营  这里是火狐一号
Green Base, Foxfire One. Green Base, Foxfire One.
我们开始买卖了  完毕
We are open for business, over.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
别告诉我你没到我的信号
Tell me you're seeing this.
她发信号了
DUALLA: She's relaying a message.
有情况了
It's Centurions!
星芭被击中了
Starbuck's been hit!
再说一次  星芭正在坠落
I say again, Starbuck's going down!
在圣卷经文上没有什么关于这个眼的说法
There's really not much more on the Eye in these scriptures,
可有些关于这座庙的有趣说法
but there's several interesting stories about the Temple.
听这里
Listen to this...
"五名牧师的身后雕塑了五根柱子
"Five pillars of the Temple were fashioned after
用来献祭给不能透露姓名的..."
"the Five Priests devoted to the One Whose Name Cannot... "
劳拉
Laura.
怎么了?
What?
和其他赛昂人一起过来的那个我们称为布玛尔的人
The Cylon we know as Boomer arrived with the others.
她告诉我们的莎伦  那个小孩还活着
She told our Sharon that her child was alive,
而那个小孩现在一艘赛昂人的基地之星上
and that she was onboard one of the Cylon baseships.
同时小孩也在你新卡布里卡的学校里出现过
And that she had been seen on New Caprica, in your school.
那小孩还活着
The child is alive.
是的  是的
Yes, yes.
是的  我是当时把她养在学校里
The child was at the school. Yes, I kept her there.
并且事后怀疑她被赛昂人捕获了
And we suspected that the Cylons captured her during the exodus
是的  这是真的
from New Caprica. Yes, it's true.
听着  你需要明白这件事是当...
Listen, the thing you might want to know is that when...
你知道我们是怎么过来的吗?
Do you have any idea what we've gone through?
你们所有人
You, of all people...
知道失去孩子是什么感觉吗?
Know what it's like to lose a child.
不同的是你的孩子还活着
The difference is, your child is still alive.
最后… 希望你们能感到高兴
Eventually, I hope you become grateful of that.
我想见她
I want to see her.
你说她坠落是什么意思  坠落在哪?
What do you mean she's gone down? Gone down where?
在峡谷北部的什么地方
Somewhere in the North Valley.
好了  让你的人准备好
Okay, get your men on the line.
装满弹药   哇 哇
Full ammo loads. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
他们从北边过来了  卡拉怎么办
They're coming from the north. What about Kara?
我们要组织个救援队  对不对?
We're gonna set up a rescue party, right?
不
No.
我们没有人手 我们只能坚守岗位
We don't have the manpower. We have to defend the position.
李  她可能会死在那的
Lee, she could be dying out there.
是  我知道  山姆  我知道
Yeah, I know that, Sam. I know.
但是我们在这 赛昂人还在向这边行军
But we are thin on the ground here and the Cylons are on the march.
我们救不了她 我们只能坚守岗位
We can't help her. We have to hold our positions.
你他妈的疯了吗?
Are you out of your frakking mind?
刚从雷达中捕捉到六架突袭机从赛昂人舰队中出发
We just picked up six Heavy Raiders falling away from the Cylon fleet.
明显目的地是那星球
Definitely heading down toward the planet.
我不懂
I don't get it.
它们应该知道我们能看到的
They have to know we see them.
它们在考验我们
They're testing us.
想知道我们说用核弹攻击这颗星球是不是装腔作势
Want to know if we're bluffing about nuking the planet.
幸运的是我们在使诈
Well, unfortunately, we are bluffing.
我们有吗?
Are we?
Hoshi先生    是  长官
Mr. Hoshi. HOSHI: Aye, sir.
下令将地面攻击核弹装入4至10号发射管道
Order nuclear ground strike missiles into launch tubes four through ten.
是  长官
HOSHI: Aye, sir.
以下是核弹攻击命令
This is a nuclear mission order.
少校是对的
The Major's right.
在我们要坚守这里的时候 我们没有额外的兵力能分出去
We don't have any troops to spare if we're gonna hold this position.
放弃这里!
Screw this position!
听着  我们可以占据这些山  开展游击战
Listen, we can take those hills, use guerilla tactics,
这是我一直提议的!
that's what I've been talking about this whole time.
够了  这不是个计划   我们领了命令了 我们要...
No, that is not the mission. We have our orders. We are stronger...
你他妈是谁啊  是他妈的木头脑袋大兵?
What are you, some gods-damn wind-up tin soldier?
我们说的是我老婆      对  我知道她是谁!
This is my wife we're talking about! Yeah, I know who she is!
并且我了解她 在意她 比你他妈的早多了!
And I have known her and cared about her a hell of a lot longer than you!
别教训我!  你他妈的想做什么就做什么吧!
Don't start lecturing me! You can do whatever the frak you want!
我会去找我的老婆
I am going after my wife!
导弹装载完毕  上将
Missiles are loaded, Admiral.
打开发射槽口
Open launch tube doors.
发射槽已打开  上将
Doors are open, Admiral.
你在干吗?
What are you doing?
准备用核弹轰掉这颗星球
I'm getting ready to nuke the planet.
侦测到有辐射发出 他们打开了核弹发射槽
Radiological detection. They've opened their missile doors.
他在装腔作势
He's bluffing.
我不能让你那么做  山姆        我不需要你的鬼许可
I can't let you do that, Sam. I am not asking you for permission.
马修斯军士
Sergeant Mathias.
输入发射坐标:代码3-Bravo
Load target package Three-Bravo.
设定爆心投影点为地下建筑物
Set ground zero for the underground structure.
我们是在准备牺牲李吗?
ROSLIN: Are we prepared to sacrifice Lee?
他们正在输入发射坐标
They're loading a targeting package.
只是装腔作势  别被他吓着了
It's a bluff. Don't let him rattle you.
我们的风险太大  不可接受  召回突袭机
The risk to us is unacceptable. Turn back the Raiders.
不能召回他们 他不会发射的
The ships cannot turn back. He won't launch it.
戴安娜和波塔尔下定主意要去地面
And D'Anna was explicit that she and Baltar make it to the planet's surface.
那么  这才是真正的目的?
CAPRICA SIX: So, is that what all this is really about?
天空终于打开了大门  他们看到了眼睛
And the heavens opened up and they saw the Eye,
但是那眼睛在哪呢?
but where is that frakking Eye?
你在开我玩笑?  你要准备开枪打我?
Are you kidding me? You gonna shoot me now?
我不能让你走 我需要你
I can't let you go. I need you on the line.
我需要你来指挥民众
I need you commanding those civilians.
抱歉  山姆  但是你不能走
I'm sorry, Sam, but you cannot go.
我也很抱歉 少校 但是你阻止不了我
I'm sorry, too, Major, but you can't stop me.
发射核弹许可已被授权
Release of nuclear weapons is now authorized.
长官
Sir.